Register of the Alfred Kohlberg papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence and Subject File, 1944-1960 (Boxes 1-207)
  - Dewey, Special Committee, 1948
    3 folders. Includes Herbert Brownell, Jr.
  - Dewey - Brownell, 1944-1946 (Box 54)
  - Diem, Ngo-Dinh [See: Vietnam]
  - Dickson, Alice
  - Dies Committee report, 2 folders
  - Digest ( The Current Digest of the Soviet Press)
  - Dingell, John D.
  - Dirksen, Everett M.
  - Disarmament
  - Ditmars, Walter
  - Djilas, Milovan
  - Dobbs, Zygmund
  - Dobriansky, Lev E.
  - Documents, 2 folders
  - Dodd, Bella
  - Dodd, Thomas J.
  - Dodd, William E.
  - Dodds, Harold W.
  - Dohrenwend, Otto E.
  - Dolbier, Maurice
  - Dolivet, Louis
  - Donald, W. H. (Box 55)
  - Dondero, George A., 2 folders
  - Donovan, William J.
  - Dooley, Thomas E.
  - Dooman, Eugene
  - Dos Passos, John
  - Doubleday and Company, Inc.
  - Dougherty, William V.
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagen
  - Douglas, Paul H.
  - Douglas, William O.
  - Dover Group
  - Dream ("My Dream of World History...")
  - Dresser, Robert A.
  - Drummond, Roscoe
  - Drumright, Everett F.
  - DuBois, W. E. B.
  - Dudintsev, Vladimir
  - Duggan, Lawrence
  - Duke University
  - Dulles, Allen W.
  - Dulles, Foster Rhea
  - Dulles, John Foster
    - 1957-1958
    - 1948-1956 (Box 56)
    - 1951 (Box 57)
  - Dunn, Leslie C.
  - Dunner, Joseph
  - Duran, Gustavo
  - Durdin, Tillman and Peggy, 4 folders
  - Durdin, Tillman (Box 58)
  - Duvall, Josephine
  - Dwyer, R. J.
  - E, miscellaneous
    - 1958
    - 1955-1957
    - 1953-1954
    - 1951-1952
    - 1949-1950
    - 1945-1948
    - 1945-1949
  - East and West Association [See also: Pearl Buck]
  - Eastern World
  - Eastland, James O.
  - Eaton, Charles A.
  - Eaton, Cyrus
    - 1959
    - 1957-1958 (Box 59)
  - Economic Club of New York
  - Economic Cooperation Administration, 2 folders
  - Ecton, Zales N.
  - Eddy, Sherwood
  - Edelstein
  - Eden, Anthony
  - Edison, Charles, 4 folders
  - Edson, Peter
  - Education
  - Edwards, Frank
  - Eichin, Fred C.
  - Einstein, Albert, 2 folders
  - Eisendrath, Maurice N.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - 1956-1958
    - 1952-1955, 5 folders (Box 60)
  - Eisler, Gerhard
  - Elections
  - Electoral College
  - Electronics Corporation of America
  - Elegant, Robert S.
  - Eliot, George Fielding, 2 folders
  - ELLENTUCH
  - Eleosser, Leo
  - Embree, Edwin R.
  - Emeny, Brooks
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee
  - Emmerson, John Kenneth
  - Empire Trust Letter (Joseph Stagg Lawrence), 3 folders
  - Endicott, James G. and Marty Austin Endicott
  - Enemy Within, correspondence about
  - Engle, Clair
  - Entente Internationale Anticommuniste (Box 61)
  - Epstein, Israel, 2 folders
  - Epstein, Julius, 1945-1958; 3 folders
  - Estonia
  - Ethical Culture Society
  - Ethridge, Mark F.
  - European Recovery Program
  - Evans, Forrest
  - Evans, Henry S.
  - Evans, Luther R.
  - Expose, 2 folders
    - Sound recording, 1951 December 26; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.1
      A transcript is available. The transcript is more complete than the sound recording.
    - Rest of the folder is not yet described
  - F, miscellaneous
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1955-1956
    - 1953-1954
    - 1952
    - 1951 (Box 62)
    - 1950
    - 1948-1949
    - 1944-1947
    - 1946-1951
  - Fabian, Bella
  - Face the Nation
  - Facts Forum News [See also: H. L. Hunt], 1952-1956; 3 folders
  - Fagan, Myron C. [See: Cinema Educational Guild, Inc.]
  - Fairbank, John K.
  - Fall, Bernard B.
  - Far East-America Council of Commerce and Industry, Inc.
  - Far East Freedom Commission, 1953
  - Far East Trader, 1950
  - Far Eastern Association
  - Far Eastern News Letter, Emanuel Larsen, 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Far Eastern Survey, Institute of Pacific Relations, 2 folders
  - Farago, Ladislas
  - Farley, James A., 2 folders
  - Farnsworth, Clyde A.
  - Fast, Howard
  - Faymonville, Philip R.
  - FBI (Federal Bureau of Investigation), 2 folders
  - Federal Communications Commission
  - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies
  - Feighan, Michael A.
  - Feis, Herbert
  - Feller, Abraham H.
  - Fellers, Bonner, 2 folders
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation
  - Felshin, Max
  - Feng Yu-hsiang
  - Ferguson, Homer E., 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Fertig, Lawrence
  - Feuer, Lewis S.
  - Field, Frederick V.
  - The Fields, Noel, Herta and Hermann
  - Fierlinger, Prime Minister Zdenek
  - Fierst, Herbert
  - Fifth Amendment
  - Films
  - Finletter, Thomas K.
  - First Freedom International
  - First National City Bank of New York, Howard C. Sheperd, Chairman of the Board
  - Fischer, Louis
  - Fischer, Ruth, 3 folders
  - Fish, Hamilton
  - Fisher, Galen M.
  - Fisher, Harold H.
  - Fisher, Paul C.
  - Fisher, Mrs. Welthy Honsinger
  - Flanders, Ralph E., 2 folders
  - Flexner, Abraham
  - Flies
  - Fluegel, Edna
  - Flynn, John T.
  - Flynn, Thomas F.
  - Folsom, Frank (Box 65)
  - For America
  - Ford, Francis X.
  - Ford Corporation and the Ford Motor Company
  - Ford Foundation, 1953-1958; 7 folders
  - Fordham University
  - Foreign aid study (Box 66)
  - Foreign Affairs
  - Foreign Affairs, Committee on, 2 folders
  - Foreign Policy Alliance
  - Foreign Policy Association
    - 1956-1959, 3 folders
    - 1937-1955, 3 folders (Box 67)
  - Foreign Policy Bulletin
    - 1946-1949, 4 folders
    - 1936-1943 (Box 68)
  - Foreign Policy Reports, 1934-1947; 4 folders
  - Foreign Relations, U.S. Senate Committee on, 2 folders
  - Forman, Harrison
    - Dictation of letters, 1952 February 4; 1 disc (Box 69)
      Use copy reference number: 61002.2
      Disc contains 6 "tracks" and a total of 24 dictated letters: Track 1 (10 letters); Track 2 (3 letters); Track 3 (6 letters); Track 4 (2 letters); Track 5 (1 letter); Track 6 (2 letters).
    - Rest of folder is not yet described
  - Formosa riots
  - Forrestal, James, 2 folders
  - Fortune Magazine
  - Fosdick, Raymond
  - Foster, W. C.
  - Foster, William Z.
  - Foundation for Economic Education, Inc.
  - Foundation to Defeat Communism
  - Fox, Victor J. [See also: Pentagon case]
  - Frank, Waldo
  - Frankfurt
  - Frankfurter, Felix
  - Franks, Sir Oliver
  - Free China Press, Inc. [See: Shih-chi Wu]
  - Free Germany Committee
  - Free Pacific Association, Inc.
  - Freedom, Virginia Starr, 2 folders
  - Freedom and Union
  - Freedom Front [5 folders], 1950-1957
  - Freedom House
  - Freedom Press publications
  - Freedoms Foundation, Kenneth Dale Wells
  - Freeman, Miller (Box 70)
  - The Freeman, 1950-1956; 8 folders
  - French, Mrs. Earl R.
  - Friedman, Benjamin
  - Friends of China, Inc.
  - Friends of Democracy [See: L. M. Birkhead]
  - Friends Service Committee [See: American Friends Service Committee]
  - Fritchman, Rev. Stephen H.
  - Fulbright, William J., 2 folders (Box 71)
  - Fuller, J. F. C.
  - Fund for the Republic, 4 folders
  - G, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1957-1958
    - 1955-1956
    - 1953-1954
    - 1952
    - 1950-1951 (Box 72)
    - 1949
    - * and **
  - Gaither, Rowan H.
  - Gaither Committee
  - Galbraith, J. Kenneth
  - Gallagher, Buell
  - Gallop Poll
  - Gans, Leonard S.
  - Garrity, Devin (Devin-Adair Company)
  - Garside, B. A., 2 folders
  - Gates, Artemus
  - Gates, John
  - Gaulle, General Charles de
  - Gayn, Mark
  - Geneva
  - George, Harrison
  - George, Walter
  - Gerlach, Talitha
  - Germany, Federal Republic of
  - Get-Out-Of-China-Week, 1946 September 22-28
  - Getts, Clark H.
  - Gibarti, Louis
  - Gibson, Tom L.
  - Gideonse, Harry D.
  - Gilbert, Rodney, 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Gilchrist, Huntington
  - Gillette, Guy M.
  - Gilmore, Eddy
  - Gimbel, Elinor
  - Gipson, J. H., 1947-1957; 5 folders
  - Girl Scouts of America
  - Gitlow, Benjamin
  - Glasser, Harold
  - Gluck, Maxwell Henry
  - Goddard, W. G.
  - Goddard College
  - Goel, Sita Ram
  - Goette, John
  - Golden Rule Foundation
  - Gould, Randall
  - Goldwater, Barry
  - Golovachev, M. P.
  - Goodrich, L. Carrington
  - Goodwin, William J. (Box 74)
  - Gordon, Rosalie M.
  - Gore, Leroy
  - Gould, Kenneth
  - Gouzenko, Igor
  - Government Operations, Committee on (House of Representatives)
  - Governmental Affairs
  - Graci, Mr. (member, New York State Assembly)
  - Graham, Billy
  - Graham, Frank P., 2 folders
  - Grajdanzev, Andrew J.
  - Grant, Francis R.
  - Graves, Mortimer, 2 folders
  - Gray, Barry
    - Sound recording, 1952 May 6; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.6
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - Great Books Foundation
  - Greater New York Fund
  - Green, Abner
  - Green, Andrew Wilson
  - Green, Montgomery
  - Green, O. M. ( London Observer)
  - Green, Theodore F. (Box 75)
  - Greenberg, Michael
  - Greene, Graham
  - Greenspun, Hank
  - Gregerson, Magnus I.
  - Grew, Joseph C.
  - Griswold, A. Whitney
  - Gropper, William
  - Gross, Ernest A.
  - Groves, Leslie R.
  - Gruenther, Alfred M.
  - Guatemala
  - Guerard, Albert
  - Guillain, Robert
  - Guild, Eugene R.
  - Guilt by association
  - Gulag
  - Gunther, John
  - Gwinn, Ralph
  - H, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1957-1958
    - 1955-1956
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952 (Box 76)
    - 1951
    - 1949-1950
    - 1948
    - 1945-1948
  - Hahn, Emily
  - Hailey, Foster
  - Haldane, J. B. S.
  - Hale, Robert
  - Halle, Louis J.
  - Hallinan, Vincent William
  - Halton, Hugh
  - Hamilton, Alice
  - Hamlin, Talbot
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
  - Haney, Lewis H.
  - Hanna, Charles M.
  - Harbison, William Albert
  - Harding, Earl
  - Harding College [See also: National Educational Program]
  - Harkness, Georgia
  - Harnischfeger, Walter
  - Harper and Brothers
  - Harper's Magazine
  - Harriman, W. Averell, 2 folders (Box 77)
  - Harrington, Donald
  - Harriss, Robert M.
  - Harsch, Joseph C.
  - Hartford Courant
  - Hartnett, Vincent
  - Harvard University, 2 folders
  - Hawaii, 2 folders
  - Hawkes, Albert W.
  - Hay, John
  - Hays, Wayne
  - Hazard, John
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 2 folders
  - Healy, Cletus
  - Hearst, William R., Jr. and Randolph Hearst, 2 folders
  - Heatwole, Oliver W.
  - Hecht, Frank
  - Heffron, Edward J.
  - Heimlich, William F.
  - Heinsohn, A. G.
  - Henderson, Loy
  - Henry, Patrick
  - Herald Tribune
    - Correspondence, 1945-1959; 7 folders (Box 78)
    - Book reviews
    - Clippings, 3 folders
    - Correspondence and clippings, 1951 July - 1955; 7 folders (Box 79)
    - Clippings, 1949 September - 1951; 5 folders (Box 80)
    - Correspondence and clippings, 1949 January - August; 7 folders (Box 81)
    - Clippings, 1947 September - 1948 December; 16 folders (Box 82)
    - Clippings, 1945 - 1947 August; 19 folders (Box 83)
    - Clippings, 1945 April - December; 5 folders (Box 84)
    - Clippings, 1944 - 1945 March; 3 folders (Box 85)
  - Herling, John
  - Herrick, Elinore
  - Hester, Hugh B.
  - Hewitt, George
  - Hickenlooper, Bourke B.
  - Higgins, Marguerite
  - High, Stanley [See: Reader's Digest]
  - Highlander Folk School
  - Hildebrandt, Rainer
  - Hilf, Rudolph
  - Hillman, Alex
  - Hillman, Sidney
  - Hindus, Maurice
  - Hinton, William H., Joan Chase, Jean
  - Herter, Christian A.
  - Hiss, Alger
  - Hiss, Alger (Box 86)
  - Ho Chi Minh
  - Ho, P. H.
  - Ho, Ying-chin (Chinese delegation, UN, military)
  - Hocking, William Ernest
  - Hoffman, Paul
  - Hoffmann, J. Henry B.
  - Hofstadter, Samuel H.
  - Holland, William L.
  - Holmes, Ann C.
  - Hong Kong newspapers
  - Hong Kong Standard, 2 folders
  - Honolulu
  - Hooker, West
  - Hoover, Herbert, 3 folders
  - Hoover, John Edgar, 2 folders
  - Hopkins, Harry
  - Hopkins, John Jay
  - Horton, Philip
    - Sound recording, 1952 May 5; 1 disc
      Use copy reference number: 61002.5
      Folder indicates "6 disks," however only one disk present.
    - Rest of folder not yet described
  - Hornbeck, Stanley, 3 folders
  - Horton, Mildred McAfee
  - Houston, Texas, newspapers
  - Hovde, Bryn J., President, The New School (Box 87)
  - Howard, Harry Paxton
  - Howard, Roy and Jack, Scripps-Howard newspapers, 3 folders
  - Howe, Quincy
  - Howley, Frank L.
  - Hoyt, Palmer [See: Denver Post]
  - Hromadka, Josef L.
  - Hsia, C. L., 2 folders
  - Hsieh, P. C.
  - Hsu, Ai-chu
  - Hsu, Leonard
  - Hsu, Tsung-chih
  - Hu Shin, 3 folders
  - Hu, William
  - Huang, Shao-ku
  - Hudson, G. F.
  - Hughes, Langston
  - Hughes, Paul
  - Hughes, Richard
  - Hukvalahaps
  - Human Events
    - 1959
    - 1950-1957, 8 folders (Box 88)
    - 1946-1949, 4 folders (Box 89)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, 2 folders
  - Humphreys, Robert
  - Hungary [See also: Bela Fabian]
  - Hunter, Clarence E., 2 folders
  - Hunter, Edward, 1950-1958; 4 folders
  - Hurleigh, Robert F.
  - Hurley, General Patrick J., 4 folders (Box 90)
  - Huss, Pierre
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard
  - Hutheesing, Raja
  - Hutton, Edward F.
  - I, miscellaneous
    - 1958
    - 1954-1958
    - 1949-1953
    - 1945-1948
  - Iberica
  - Ickes, Harold
  - Illig, William
  - The Independent American
  - Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences and Professions
  - India
  - Indianapolis, 2 folders
  - Indochina
  - Indonesia, 2 folders
  - INDUSCO
  - Industrial College of the Armed Forces (Box 91)
  - Industrial Security Institute
  - Infantry Journal
  - Inform [See: Ulius L. Amoss]
  - Ingebretsen, James C., 2 folders
  - Inman, Samuel Guy
  - Inslerman, Hans
  - Institute for Advanced Study, The
  - Institute of Chinese Culture [See also: Father Ronald Norris]
  - Institute of Pacific Relations
    - Lists of books
    - 1957-1958
    - 1953-1956
    - Temporary
    - Correspondence regarding study of the IPR publications, 1944-1946 (Box 92)
    - 1942-1950
    - To 1949
    - 1950-1952
    - Photostats, 1941, 1944-1947
    - Letters, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Intellectuals
  - Intelligence Digest
    - 1956
    - 1955
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952
    - 1951
    - 1950 (Box 94)
    - 1948, 1949
  - International Commission of Jurists
  - International Cooperation Administration
  - International Council of Christian Churches [See: Carl McIntire]
  - International documents
  - International Friendship Through Religion
  - International Labor Organization (ILO)
  - International Latex Corporation
  - International Longshoreman's Association (ILA)
  - International Missionary Council
  - International News Service
  - International Publishers
  - International Relations Magazine
  - International Rescue Committee [See: David Martin and Leo Cherne]
  - International Research on Communist Techniques, Inc. [See NTS]
  - International Review Service
  - International Statistical Bureau, Inc.
  - International Trade Organization
  - Iran
  - Isaacs, Harold R.
  - Isaacs, Stanley
  - Isbrandtsen
  - Ives, Irving M.
  - J, miscellaneous
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1955-1956
    - 1953-1954
    - 1950-1952 (Box 95)
    - 1945-1949
    - 1947-1948
  - Jack, Homer A.
  - Jacoby, Annalee
  - Jaffe, Philip J.
  - Jahoda, Marie
  - James, Roy E.
  - Japan
  - Japan, Emperor
  - Japan, 1945, New York Post clippings
  - Japan Society
  - Japanese Committee for Democracy, 2 folders
  - Japanese Peace Treaty, 1951
  - Japanese Peace Treaty (Box 96)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 2 folders
  - Jefferson School
  - Jenner, William
    - 1954-1958, 6 folders
    - 1949-1952, 3 folders (Box 97)
  - Jerome, V. J.
  - Jessup, Philip C., 1948-1957; 4 folders
  - Jewish Information Bureau
  - Jewish Life
  - Jewish Newsletter
  - Jewish War Veterans
  - Johns Hopkins University, 2 folders
  - Johnson, Earl J.
  - Johnson, Gerald W., 2 folders
  - Johnson, Joseph E.
  - Johnson, Lyndon
  - Johnson, U. Alexis
  - Johnston, Eric
  - Johnston, J. Edward
  - Joint Anti-Fascist Bleeding Hearts for Ryan
  - Joint Committee Against Communism in New York, 2 folders (Box 98)
  - Joliot-Curie, Frederic
  - Jordan, George R.
  - Jordan, Virgil [See: National Industrial Conference Board]
  - Jorden, William J.
  - Journal American (a New York newspaper)
    - 1951 March - 1958, 10 folders
    - 1945-1950, 10 folders (Box 99)
  - Joy, C. Turner (Box 100)
  - Judd, Orrin G.
  - Judd, Walter H., 1943-1960; 6 folders
  - Judiciary Committee, House of Representatives
  - Judiciary Committee, U.S. Senate, 3 folders
  - Judiciary hearing, 1953
  - Jung, Harry
  - Justice Department, 2 folders
  - K, miscellaneous
    - 1959 (Box 101)
    - 1956-1958
    - 1954-1955
    - 1952-1953
    - 1950-1951
    - to 1949
    - K*
  - Kaghan, Theodore
  - Kahn, Albert E.
  - Kahn, J. Kesner
  - Kallen, H. M.
  - Kalmuk Committee
  - Kaltenborn, H. V.
  - Kamp, Joseph P.
  - Kanin, Garson
  - Kantorowicz, Alfred
  - Kashmir (Box 102)
  - Kates, Frederick Ward
  - Katyn Forest Massacre
  - Kearney, James F., 3 folders
  - Kee, John
  - Keefe, Frank B.
  - Keenleyside, Hugh L., 2 folders
  - Kefauver, Estes
  - Keller, James
  - Kemp, Arthur
  - Kempton, Murray
  - Kennan, George F.
  - Kennard, J. Spencer
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Kenney, George C.
  - Kent, Rockwell
  - Kenyon, Dorothy
  - Kerensky, Alexander
  - Kerner, Robert J.
  - Kershner, Howard [See: Christian Freedom Foundation]
  - Kersten, Charles J., 2 folders
  - Kestnbaum, Meyer
  - Keyser, David
  - Khokhlov, Nikolai
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S., 2 folders (Box 103)
  - Kilgore, Harley M.
  - Killian, James R.
  - Kimmel, Husband E., 2 folders
  - King, Willford I. [See: Committee for Constitutional Government]
  - King-Hall, Stephen
  - Kingsley, J. Donald
  - Kinmond, William [See: Toronto Globe and Mail]
  - Kirby, E. S.
  - Kirk, Grayson L.
  - Kirkpatrick, Frank, 3 folders
  - Kissinger, Henry A.
  - Kizer, B. H.
  - KKK (Ku Klux Klan)
  - Klaus, Ida and Sam (Box 104)
  - Klein, Arthur
  - Klein, Henry H.
  - Klein, Julius (Chicago)
  - Klein, Julius (Washington, D. C.)
  - Knight, Goodwin
  - Knight, O. A.
  - Knowland, William F., 1949-1958; 5 folders
  - Koen, Ross Y.
  - Koether, George
  - Kohlberg, Jerome
  - Kohlberg, Roberta
  - Kohler, Foy D.
  - Kohn, Hans
  - Koo, V. K. Wellington, 2 folders
  - Korea
    - 1953-1956, 3 folders
    - 1947-1952, 6 folders (Box 105)
  - Korean Embassy
  - Kornfeder, Joseph Zack, 1948-1955; 2 folders
  - Kornfeder, Joseph Zack (Box 106)
  - Kramer, Stanley
  - Krock, Arthur, 2 folders
  - Kung, H. H., 2 folders
  - Kung Peng
  - Kunzig, Robert L.
  - Kuomintang-Communist relations
  - Kwei, C. S.
  - Kuprianou, Spyros R.
  - L, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1956-1958
    - 1954-1955
    - 1952-1953
    - 1950-1951
    - 1948-1949 (Box 107)
    - 1945-1947
    - L*
  - Labin, Suzanne
  - Labor
  - Labor, United States Department of
  - Labouisse, Henry Richardson
  - Lacy, William S. B.
  - Ladejinsky, Wolf
  - Lamont, Corliss
  - La Moore, Parker
  - Lampell, Millard
  - Land reform
  - Landauer, Henri, Lily and Susi
  - Landman, Amos
  - Landon, Alf, 2 folders
  - Landy, Eugene W.
  - Lange, Oscar
  - Langer, William
  - Langmuir, Irving
  - Lansing, Robert
  - Lapham, Roger D. (Box 108)
  - Larrazabal, Wolfgang
  - Larsen, Emmanuel S.
  - Laski, Harold J.
  - Lasky, Melvin J.
  - Lasky, Victor
  - Latimer, Ira
  - Latin America
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1941-1955; 5 folders
  - LaTocsin
  - Lau, Ching S.
  - Laurens, Jorge Prieto
  - Lausche, Frank
  - Lauterbach, Richard E.
  - Lavin, Irene
  - Law in Communist China
  - Lawrence, David, 1957-1958
  - Lawrence, David, 1945-1956; 4 folders (Box 109)
  - Leaf, Earl, 2 folders
  - League for Industrial Democracy, Inc.
  - League of Women Voters
  - Leahy, Maurice (The Oriel Society)
  - Lee, Bum Suk
  - Lee, Edwin
  - Lee, J. Bracken
  - Lee, Michael [See also: New York Daily News]
  - Lee, William Yinson
  - Leebrick, K. C.
  - LeFevre, Robert T.
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1950-1955; 3 folders
  - Lei Chen
  - Lemelin, Emile
  - Lempert, Frank
  - Lend-lease
  - Leonhard, Wolfgang
  - Leonov, Leonid
  - Lerner, Max
  - Leslie, Kenneth
  - Lewis, Alfred Barker
  - Lewis, Fulton, Jr., 3 folders
  - Lewis, Harry E. (Box 110)
  - Li Mi, General
  - Li Tsung-jen, General
  - Libel
  - Liberal Party of the state of New York
  - Liberty Book Club
  - Library of Congress, 2 folders
  - Lie, Trygve
  - Lieberman, Henry R. [See also: New York Times], 4 folders
  - Liebman, Marvin
  - Life Lines
  - Life Magazine
    - 1955-1958
    - 1945-1954, 5 folders (Box 111)
  - Lilienthal, David E.
  - Limb, Ben C.
  - Lin Yutang, 2 folders
  - Lincoln, Abraham
  - Lincoln Brigade
  - Lindeman, C. B.
  - Lindeman, Edward G.
  - Lindsay, Michael
  - Linebarger, Paul M. A.
  - Ling, C. P. (Ling, Chen-ping)
  - Lippitt, Elizabeth
  - Lippmann, Walter
    - 1958-
    - 1952-1957, 4 folders
  - Lists
    - Purged U.S.S.R. leading figures (Box 112)
    - War criminals (People's Liberation Army)
    - Asian aid
  - Littell, Norman M.
  - Litvinov, Maxim, 2 folders
  - Liu Shao-Chi
  - Livingston, Goodhue, Jr.
  - Lobbying Committee, 2 folders
  - Lockwood, William W.
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 2 folders
  - Lodge, John Davis, 2 folders
  - Loeb, James
  - London Economist
  - London Daily Mirror
  - London newspapers
  - London Observer (Box 113)
  - (London) The Spectator
  - London Times
  - Long, Hamilton A.
  - Look Magazine, 2 folders
  - Lorch, Lee and Grace
  - Lord and Taylor
  - Lorwin, Val
  - Los Angeles (trips by Kohlberg)
  - Los Angeles Examiner
  - Los Angeles Herald Express
  - Los Angeles Mirror
  - Los Angeles News
  - Los Angeles Times
  - Louisville Courier-Journal
  - Lovestone, Jay
  - Lowe, C. H.
  - Lowell, Benjamin
  - Lowell, Ralph
  - Lowenstein and Sons, Inc.
  - Lowenthal, Max, 2 folders
  - Lowman, Myers G. (Circuit Riders), 1952-1958; 3 folders
  - Lowry, Charles W. (Box 114)
  - Lubell, Samuel
  - Luce, Clare Boothe and Henry Robinson, 3 folders
  - Lurie, Harry L.
  - Lynd, Hans
  - Lyon, Elsie Chung
  - Lyons, Eugene, 2 folders
  - Lyons, Florence (Fowler)
  - M, miscellaneous
    - 1959
    - 1958
    - 1957
    - 1956
    - 1955 July-December (Box 115)
    - 1955 January-June
    - 1954
    - 1953
    - 1952 July-December
    - 1952 January-June
    - 1951
    - 1950
    - 1949
    - 1948
    - 1947 (Box 116)
    - 1946
    - 1945-1951
  - MacArthur, General Douglas, 4 folders
  - MacDuffie, Marshall
  - Mackay, John
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Macy, W. Kingsland
  - Madison (Wisconsin) Capitol Times
  - Magnuson, Warren B. [See: TRADE for correspondence and clippings]
  - Magruder, Frank Abbott
  - Makaroff, V. S.
  - Malenkov, Georgi M.
  - Malin, Patrick Murphy
  - Malinovsky, Rodion Y.
  - Malkin, Maurice
  - Mallan, Lloyd
  - Mallon, Paul
  - Malone, George
  - Maloof, Louis J.
  - Manchester Union Leader
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1945-1958; 5 folders (Box 117)
  - Manila Pact (Box 118)
  - Manion, Clarence, 2 folders
  - Mansfiled, Mike, 3 folders
  - Mao Tse-tung, 2 folders
  - Maoist line
  - Maps
  - Maps (Box 119)
  - Map of China, 1945-1946
  - Marcus, J. Anthony, 2 folders
  - Marine Corps, U.S., 2 folders
  - Marks, Norman L.
  - Marquette University
  - Marshall, General George C.
    4 folders. Includes Marshall Plan.
  - Marshall, J. Howard
  - Martin, David
  - Martin, Joseph W.
  - Marx, Karl
  - Marymount College
  - Massachusetts Special Commission on Communism
  - Matthews, Herbert L.
  - Matthews, J. B.
    - 1950-1957
    - 1951-1957, 2 folders
  - Matthews, Jason and Marcia (Box 120)
  - Matusow, Harvey
  - Maurer, Herrymon
  - Mayer, Milton
  - McArdle, John Philip
  - McCarran, Pat, 1949-1954; 4 folders
  - McCarran, Pat: McCarran Act (Box 121)
  - McCarthy, Joseph R.
    - 1955-1957, 4 folders
    - 1954 April-September (Box 122)
    - Clippings, 2 folders
    - Clippings (Box 123)
    - 1954 January-March
    - 1953
    - 1952
    - 1950-1952, 8 folders (Box 124)
  - McCarthy, Mrs. Joseph R.
  - McClatchy, John H.
  - McCloy, John J. (Box 125)
  - McConaughty, James L.
  - McCormack, Anne O'Hare
  - McCormack, John W.
  - McCrary, Tex
  - McCune, Shannon
  - McElory, Neil H.
  - McGrath, J. Howard
  - McGraw-Hill
  - McIntire, Carl
  - McKee, Frederick C., 2 folders
  - McKeever, Porter